Draper Corporation Glass Plate Negatives 6612 GPN
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series A: 5 x 7 inch negatives.
  - Spoon and potato race, 1925 (Box 61, Folder 1224)
    Negative no.A1224. August 1925. Image shows three women approaching the finish line of the race where containers are in place for the potatoes to be placed. The idea apparently is to fill the container with potatoes. Note a number of potatoes on the ground. Several judges watch from the sideline, while another judge stands close to finish line. Spectators line the course in the background; a house can be seen in the background as well. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 5, Item 1224 for print of this negative.
  - Handoff in relay race, 1925 (Box 61, Folder 1225)
    Negative no.A1225. August 1925. Image shows a man on the right in shorts and singlet waiting for the handoff baton while two other runners have passed him on the left; a judge in a straw hat stands at the right. Spectators are lined up in the background with a house and flagpole in the distance. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 5, Item 1225 for print of this negative.
  - Girls' Potato Race, 1925 (Box 61, Folder 1226)
    Negative no.A1226. August 1925. Image depicts about six girls, engaged in a potato race. Three girls are picking up their potatoes while three or more are racing back and forth. Spectators in background. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 5, Item 1226 for print of this negative.
  - Handoff in relay race, 1925 (Box 61, Folder 1227)
    Negative no.A1227. August 1925. Image depicts two young men (numbers 41 and 24 on the back of their singlets) waiting for the handoff baton while another man races off with his baton. Two judges with straw hats stand at the right; spectators and flagpole in background. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Box 66, Negative 1530, Negative 1531, Negative 1533, and Negative 1534. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 5, Item 1227 for print of this negative.
  - Girls' race, 1925 (Box 61, Folder 1228)
    Negative no.A1228. August, 1925. Image shows six girls in the middle of the race; girls are wearing dresses except for one that may be in pants. Spectators and flagpole in background. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 5, Item 1228 for print of this negative.
  - Infants' race, 1925 (Box 61, Folder 1229)
    Negative no.A1229. August 1925. Image shows approximately six small children, both boys and girls, in the middle of a race. Children are about five to seven years of age. Spectators and flagpole in background. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 5, Item 1229 for print of this negative.
  - Girl Scouts game, 1925 (Box 61, Folder 1230)
    Negative no.A1230. August 1925. Image shows five or six Girl Scouts engaged in a game of rolling a ring with a stick; girls are dressed in a uniform with hat. Two adults appear to be judging; spectators are watching from the sideline (on left) with flagpole in rear. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 5, Item 1230 for print of this negative.
  - Girl Scouts race, 1925 (Box 61, Folder 1231)
    Negative no.A1231. August 1925. Image shows a scout appearing to push a round ring with a stick. Other scouts cheer her on from sidelines in the right background. A leader, who may be the judge, watches near the racer. Spectators also line the course; a house and a flagpole can be seen in the background. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 5, Item 1231 for print of this negative.
  - Girls race, 1925 (Box 61, Folder 1232)
    Negative no.A1232. August 1925. Image shows four girls running toward finish line; they appear to be about nine or ten. Spectators line the course; a house and a flagpole can be seen in the background. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 5, Item 1232 for print of this negative.
  - High Jump, 1925 (Box 61, Folder 1234)
    Negative no.A1234. August 1925. Image shows a man attempting the high jump; he is seen just about to clear the jump. Spectators are grouped around the jump; a mill building can be glimpsed in the background. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 5, Item 1234 for print of this negative.
  - Girl Scouts' Competition, 1925 (Box 61, Folder 1242)
    Negative no.A1242. August 1925. Image shows four pairs of girls attempting to start fires by shaving wood scraps into a pile and using friction to ignite it. Hooks and cooking pots are near each pair waiting to be suspended over the fires. Judges look on and spectators stand back to watch. A flagpole is in the background of the field. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 5, Item 1242 for print of this negative.
  - Broad jump, 1925 (Box 61, Folder 1243)
    Negative no.A1243. August 1925. Image shows a man completing his landing after a broad jump. Another competitor stands just behind him on the left. Judges look on and a crowd of spectators lines the course. A flagpole is in the background of the field. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1248, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 5, Item 1243 for print of this negative.
  - Wheelbarrow race, 1925 (Box 61, Folder 1244)
    Negative no.A1244. August 1925. Image shows pairs of boys forming wheelbarrows by one holding up the legs of another who, in the front, holds a wheel. As the "driving" boy holds the other's "handle" legs and runs forward, the front wheel rotates and the "wheelbarrow" rolls along the ground. A flagpole and building can be seen in the background. Some scattered spectators line the course. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1246 and Negative 1247, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 5, Item 1244 for print of this negative.
  - Sack race, 1925 (Box 61, Folder 1245)
    Negative no.A1245. August 1925. Image shows four men wearing sacks that cover them from their feet to their necks. They are hopping toward the finish line where a judge looks on. Spectators line the course. A flagpole is in the background of the field. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 5, Item 1245 for print of this negative.
  - Wheelbarrow race, 1925 (Box 61, Folder 1246)
    Negative no.A1246. August 1925. Image shows pairs of boys forming wheelbarrows by one holding up the legs of another who, in the front, holds a wheel. As the "driving" boy holds the other's "handle" legs and runs forward, the front wheel rotates and the "wheelbarrow" rolls along the ground. A flagpole and building can be seen in the background. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1244 and Negative 1247, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 5, Item 1246 for print of this negative.
  - Wheelbarrow race, 1925 (Box 61, Folder 1247)
    Negative no.A1247. August 1925. Image shows pairs of boys forming wheelbarrows by one holding up the legs of another who, in the front, holds a wheel. As the "driving" boy holds the other's "handle" legs and runs forward, the front wheel rotates and the "wheelbarrow" rolls along the ground. A flagpole and building can be seen in the background. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1244 and Negative 1246, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 5, Item 1247 for print of this negative.
  - Broad jump competitor, 1925 (Box 61, Folder 1248)
    Negative no.A1248. August 1925. Image shows a man about to complete his landing after a broad jump. Judges look on and a crowd of spectators lines the course. A flagpole is in the background of the field. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1243, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 6, Folder 5, Item 1248 for print of this negative.
  - High jump, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 1518)
    Negative no.A1518. August 1927. Image depicts a man participating in the high jump, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The man is just clearing the high jump bar. Spectators, both male and female, watch in the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1519, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 7, Folder 1, Item 1518 for print of this negative.
  - High jump participant, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 1519)
    Negative no.A1519. August 1927. Image depicts a man engaged in the high jump, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The man has either just cleared the bar or is starting his jump. Spectators, both male and female, watch in the background and on both sides. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1518, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 7, Folder 1, Item 1519 for print of this negative.
  - Girls' potato race, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 1520)
    Negative no.A1520. August 1927. Image depicts a group of about eight girls engaged in a potato race. There are some potatoes visible on the ground; the idea is probably to get all your potatoes into your box (a row of boxes is seen on the ground on the right). Spectators watch in the background; some men standing on right may be officials of some sort. Most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1521, Negative 1522, and Negative 1523, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 7, Folder 1, Item 1520 for print of this negative.
  - Girls' potato race, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 1521)
    Negative no.A1521. August 1927. Image shows three or four girls engaged in a potato race. Some potatoes can be seen on the ground; the idea is probably to be the first to get all your potatoes into one of the boxes on the right. Spectators in background; some men standing on right are probably officials of some sort. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1520, Negative 1522, and Negative 1523, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 7, Folder 1, Item 1521 for print of this negative.
  - Girls' potato race, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 1522)
    Negative no.A1522. August 1927. Image shows a group of girls engaged in a potato race. The idea is probably to be the first to get all your potatoes into the boxes seen on the ground at the right. Spectators watch in the background. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1520, Negative 1521, and Negative 1523, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 7, Folder 1, Item 1522 for print of this negative.
  - Participants in girls' potato race, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 1523)
    Negative no.A1523. August 1927. Image shows several girls engaged in a potato race, the idea presumably to be the first to fill your box (seen on the right) with potatoes. The girl on the far left is either way ahead of the rest of the group or way behind. Spectators in background; some men standing on right, probably officials of some sort. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1520, Negative 1521, and Negative 1522, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 7, Folder 1, Item 1523 for print of this negative.
  - Scooter race, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 1524)
    Negative no.A1524. August 1927. Image depicts three young boys engaged in a scooter race on a grass track with family members and spectators lined up watching on the sideline, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing, recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 7, Folder 1, Item 1524 for print of this negative.
  - Wheelbarrow race, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 1525)
    Negative no.A1525. August 1927. Image depicts young boys engaged in wheelbarrow race. Each team consists of two boys, one of whom is the "wheelbarrow" by using his hands on a set of wheels, while his legs are held by the other boy. Spectators watch from the sidelines, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1526, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 7, Folder 1, Item 1525 for print of this negative.
  - Wheelbarrow race, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 1526)
    Negative no.A1526. August 1927. Image depicts young boys engaged in wheelbarrow race. Each team consists of two boys, one of whom is the "wheelbarrow" by using his hands on a set of wheels, while his legs are held by the other boy. Spectators watch from the sidelines, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1525, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 7, Folder 1, Item 1526 for print of this negative.
  - Infants' race, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 1527)
    Negative no.A1527. August, 1927. Image depicts about a dozen small children racing on a grassy course; spectators, male and female, watch along the sideline. The children are not infants, but probably three and four years old. Most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 7, Folder 1, Item 1527 for print of this negative.
  - Rail race, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 1528)
    Negative no.A1528. August 1927. Image depicts young boys engaged in a rail race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Teams of young boys race holding a rail on which two other boys sit. One rail lays on the grass on the left; another team seems to have had one boy fall off the "rail" in the center background. Spectators look on from the side of the field. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 7, Folder 1, Item 1528 for print of this negative.
  - Pipe race, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 1529)
    Negative no.A1529. August, 1927. Image depicts about seven men participating in a pipe race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Two of the men can be seen filling a pipe from ashes on one of the eight boxes laid out; apparently the idea of the race was to be the first to move all the ashes to another spot (out of camera range). A crowd of spectators watches in the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 7, Folder 1, Item 1529 for print of this negative.
  - Start of relay race, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 1530)
    Negative no.A1530. August 1927. Image depicts three young men at the start of a relay race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Male and female spectators line the side of the course; a flagpole is visible in the center of the image. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 1531 through Negative 1534, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 7, Folder 1, Item 1530 for print of this negative.
  - Relay race, 1927 (Box 66, Folder 1531)